<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Ravi Raja Merugu</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Ravi Raja Merugu</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Async tasks with Django + RabbitMQ + Celery</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/django-celery-rabbitmq/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/django-celery-rabbitmq/</guid><description>This is awesome, Im typing this content from the github editor just to prove myself that, i dont need to clone , edit and push to write a blog</description></item><item><title>Ask yourself: is what I'm about to do going to make people smile? If the answer is yes, then do it</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/ask-your-self/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/ask-your-self/</guid><description>On a good Monday start, I was browsing through the Linkedin posts and found a blog by Richard Brandson of Virgin Group. It says
Don&amp;rsquo;t take yourself too seriously. Instead, ask yourself: is what I&amp;rsquo;m about to do going to make people smile? If the answer is yes, then do it! - Richard Brandson, Virgin Group.
He talks more about the lovely attitude and passion you should have to start something.</description></item><item><title>Mentoring Django as a part of Free Code Camp Hyderabad Month of Code Program</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/mentoring-django-free-code-camp-hyderabad-month-of-code/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/mentoring-django-free-code-camp-hyderabad-month-of-code/</guid><description>Month of Code is a program initiated by Kapil Datta of Free Code Camp, Hyderabad. The program aims at mentoring a single/group of student on a programming stack that is considered useful by the industry and lands them into some job opportunity. The underlying sentiment is to improve to the state of development in Hyderabad as Kapil always says.
The program is Month of Code contains few programs that ranges from Data structures + Algorithms to HTML + CSS + Javascript.</description></item><item><title>Setting up Continuous testing and Continuous Integration(CI) with Jenkins in localhost</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/setting-up-jenkins-localhost/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/setting-up-jenkins-localhost/</guid><description>Jenkins is one of the coolest open-source tool. As a developer I write many codes in a day and performs many commits, pulling the code a day. I like Travis CI for opensource projects, but when it comes to private projects they charge me. So I was exploring Jenkins and realised that&amp;rsquo;s what I want for my localhost.
Continuous testing is the process of executing automated tests as part of the software delivery pipeline to obtain immediate feedback on the business risks associated with a software release candidate.</description></item><item><title>Django Fake data</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/django-fake-data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/django-fake-data/</guid><description>django-autofixture(https://github.com/gregmuellegger/django-autofixture) inserts the fake data into the models with no scripting . It gets the data up and running in single command python manage.py loadtestdata blog.BlogPost:100.
I wish the fake data is in good english, but it&amp;rsquo;s a good start.</description></item><item><title>Django - why ajax for pages ? we have Pjax</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/django-why-ajax-we-have-pjax/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/django-why-ajax-we-have-pjax/</guid><description>Pjax(https://github.com/defunkt/jquery-pjax) is a jQuery plugin a standalone JavaScript module that uses ajax (XmlHttpRequest) and pushState() to deliver a fast browsing experience.
Typically django serves each page with a entire page reload, costing performance. Using Pjax, its we convert our django application into a light weight server rendered SPA :) , Lets know how awesome is that..
Here is how to use it and code is hosted at https://github.com/rrmerugu/django-pjaxified.
Step1: Fork and Clone the repo git clone https://github.</description></item><item><title>Hello Ionic framework - a sample hydrib mobile application.</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/hello-ionic-cordova/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/hello-ionic-cordova/</guid><description>Ionic Framework as the website says is the top open source framework for building amazing mobile apps..
I&amp;rsquo;ve written a sample 3 page mobile app that can be deployed into iOS and android.
Here is how to use it and code is hosted at https://github.com/rrmerugu/hello-ionic.
Step1: Create ionic app ionic start hello_app --v2 sidemenu
Step2: Create new page ionic g page home
Step3: Configuring the pages in the app
Add new page home in src/app/app.</description></item><item><title>Integrating elasticemail.com into django project for transactional emails.</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/intergrating-elasticemail-into-django-for-transactional-emails/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/intergrating-elasticemail-into-django-for-transactional-emails/</guid><description>Elastiemail as the website says is a email delivery tools provider, you can send transactional as well as promotional emails.
I&amp;rsquo;ve written a EMAILBACKEND class that allows you to send emails in django project using elasticemail.com
Here is how to use it.
Install the package via git git install -e git+https://github.com/rrmerugu/django_elasticemail
Add django_elasticemail to INSTALLED_APPS
In settings.py add EMAIL_BACKEND = &amp;quot;django_elasticemail.mail.ElasticEmailBackend&amp;quot;
Usage 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 from django.</description></item><item><title>Hello Docker - my docker notes</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/hello-docker/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/hello-docker/</guid><description>Docker as the website homepage says is the world’s leading software containerization platform. Dockers and container tech has become a common practise in the software development. I tried it and fell in love with this for many reasons. The prime reason is it is an open-source project. Long hail opensource developers.
So I&amp;rsquo;ve experimenting on the scenrios in which i might need to use docker containers. I mostly work with Django, but the technical stack varies from simple Django + sqlite to Django + postgres + redis + celery and more.</description></item><item><title>Being a Business Analyst for one day #startuponedayrole</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/a-day-as-business-analyst/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/a-day-as-business-analyst/</guid><description>Product Feature Documentation keeps everyone in the team on the same page, so I decided to write product documentation the way a BA would do it !
This is part of my personal startup-challenge to wear the hats of individual roles of a company in a day #onedaystartuprole . I founded my first company and launching a product Invaana with the all passion and dreams like any other entrepreneur. Then I was thinking about what if I hire people, and when they join the company, how would I make sure the new bees know what exactly I mean by product and what all it should do.</description></item><item><title>#startuponedayrole challenge</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/startup-one-day-a-role-challenge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/startup-one-day-a-role-challenge/</guid><description>Being the founder. I started to work on everything by self, while my hunt for cofounder and employees is still going on. It&amp;rsquo;s tough to do Multi-tasking, you will end up doing lot things with less or sometimes poor quality. So I decided to take one role a day.
Like any other early stage startup, I started to work on everything that range from thinking the product future, coding the product, taking feedbacks and many more, that range from talking to people as marketing strategy etc.</description></item><item><title>The Story</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/the-story/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/the-story/</guid><description>If you are a theist, you think its the beauty of God, But If you are a Scientist, you think, let’s explore why its beautiful. I prefer to be the second type.
I’m a stupidly curious guy with crazy imaginations. But I’m not into everything!, I don’t care about most of the things. Honestly as bad as it sounds, I don’t even know the current President of my country. The last one I knew was Dr.</description></item><item><title>I took my first startup challenge</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/i-took-my-first-startup-challenge/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/i-took-my-first-startup-challenge/</guid><description>Taking and winning challenges always inspire you and refills yours confidence.
Since college, I’ve always wanted to create something awesome, build something big. I know that sounds like any other crazy adolescent dreams, but yeah it’s kind of!. To be honest, I’ve always wanted to become a worlds renowned Scientist. But finally I founded my first startup.
So, after few years of academic research, working as technical associate in a computational drug discovery company, IT consultant for a Bay area startup, Software developer in IIT Delhi and Head of Technology and Development for a Food tech startup.</description></item><item><title>Hello World! Welcome to my First Jekyll Blog!</title><link>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/welcome-to-my-first-jekyll-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rrmerugu.github.io/posts/welcome-to-my-first-jekyll-blog/</guid><description>Blogging isn&amp;rsquo;t my thing, and I never imagined setting up a blog using Jekyll. Recently starting the new blog with Jekyll and loving it .
I could be able to setup this blog in 4 hours :D Just amazing. I wasted an hour in these 4 hrs just because I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that changes in _config.yml will be not reload automatically like the way it happens for scss, css, html, md files.</description></item></channel></rss>